[Music]
welcome my name is BU Koto I'm a program
manager working for Microsoft and my
name is ero chiman and I'm a developer
working with BL on the Power Platform
Integrations and yes today we'll be
talking about what's new in this wave
2024 wave wave two uh between business
Central and Power Platform and we of
course should start with Power Platform
what it is you probably already are
familiar it's a set of tools from
Microsoft allowing you to build software
build various experiences without uh
coding um develop software development
coding necessary it is mostly based on
connectors and of course there are
connectors for business Central allowing
you to build uh reach for data and build
experiences on top of business Central
we have plenty of various tools and
mechanisms in that um integration area
and we won't be covering everything
today but there is a plenty of
documentation and samples uh which are
available under this link so please go
and have a look at more details today we
will be talking about few areas starting
with power automate improvements in our
integration with power automate in this
wave we start with a very basic thing
which is the linking of environments
allowing you to um annotate which
environment in power automate or or
Power Platform is the one that you would
like to use with business Central and
that is especially important for larger
customers and for those uh a linked
environment which is um a feature
available in tet admin Center will be
also honored in our integration with
power automate and for that we have a
special assisted setup page allowing you
to uh agree on that linked environment
or change it with we have another uh
feature that was rolled out recently and
that is a new action in our connector
find one record allowing you to pinpoint
to a specific record in business Central
using friendly search criteria um and
then you know continuing with your logic
in power automate and of course we also
have an action uh which is called find
records and that action allows you to uh
find a selection of records and uh and
then iterate on them within your power
automate
flow we added a lot of uh improvements
related to job queue failures uh we have
another recording uh in this set where
my colleagues are talking about uh this
whole set of features related to job
cues in this wave but specifically for
power automate we have added a new um
business event and a set of power
automate templates that will be
available for you later allowing you to
be notified when something is wrong with
your job cues this will be an
interesting feature I can assure
you we have a support for new designer
power automate right now comes with a
new designer H which allows you to use
copilot within power automate and build
your flows with the help of copilot that
is now fully enabled for business
Central and you can use the uh new
designer using our triggers uh which was
uh not possible
before speaking of co-pilot in power
automate there is also a feature that
was already discussed in the past you
might have heard about that feature that
we are working on allowing you to build
flows uh using copilot inside business
Central you can do it with within power
automate as discussed but it will be
also possible within business Central
it's just this feature is still not
ready will be coming later this wave
we have also some interesting
developments in copilot Studio the
integration between business Central and
co-pilot Studio copilot Studio allows
you to build your own co-pilot
experiences your own chatbots your your
own experiences using uh Ai and
generative Ai and that uh starts with
knowledge uh sourced from either
documents and websites or from business
business from data from business data
data coming from business Central as
well and we may we are we are making
sure that our connector Works smoothly
within uh co-pilot studio and uh is able
to connect the data and read data from
within business Central so actions and
plugins and data coming from business
Central is available in copilot Studio
you will hear more about that in uh in
the coming months as co-pilot studio and
business Central integration is uh is
being enhanced the best way to
illustrate this would be in a short demo
so let's have a look I'm in business
Central I can see my inventory what if I
would like to define a co-pilot using
copilot Studio a small co-pilot that
will help with inventory related tasks
this is new co-pilot Studio recently
released an
update uh that allows you to build copil
using generative Ai and uh there are
three important parts of this co-pilot
definition for the for the copilot I
built as you can see BC inventory helper
the first one is the description and
instructions and these are uh plain
English language instructions for the
copilot uh informing it what I expect
out of it and here you of course you can
provide more and more more instructions
the second is knowledge and then that
knowledge is in my case documentation
for business Central so I pointed
copilot Studio to business Central
Public documentation
website and then the third one is our
actions and in my case I have only one
action which is return inventory level
that action is a power automate flow
that searches for a specific item and
returns inventory level for that item
you might think about providing more and
more actions for this scenario or for
for any other scenario each of that
action could be defined as a power
automate flow you can also add different
types of knowledge in copilot Studio you
can also add Knowledge from data coming
from data verse so if business Central
data is synced to data verse that would
also work and then one important uh part
of our settings if I go to settings in
copilot
Studio very important part is this
setting for generative AI I'm allowing
this copilot to use generative AI so it
behaves differently and it uses
generative AI uh to uh figure out what
to do in the classic Mode you would have
to Define each topic and you would have
to Define each flow for the copilot or
for the bot in this new mode you can
just describe what you want the co-pilot
to do and it will do it for you the next
important thing are channels and here in
channels I have Microsoft
teams and this copilot BC inventory
helper is published already on
teams so let's try to run
it so right now I'm in Microsoft teams
and the BCT inventory helper co-pilot is
publish on teams I can start discussing
uh inventory related topics but first of
all I would like to ask for an inventory
level for a given
product I can ask a pilot about
inventory level in different
ways and it will return the answer based
on the action I defined what is
important I have never and nowhere
defined how copilot should ask the user
about a given item or how the item name
should be provided this is all generated
by copilot studio and as you can see
copilot studio is able to call business
Central action in this case my power
automate flow and return the inventory
but I can also ask about general
knowledge so now I'm asking how to use
the inventory on sales order
and in this case copilot Studio use
publicly available business Central
documentation to come up with
suggestions now let's switch gar to
powerbi we have plenty of amazing
content uh for powerbi and for that I
would like to uh hand over to
enrio thank you BL so I'm going to cover
some of the powerbi improvements that we
have done for this upcoming release and
I will be talking about some new content
that we have introduced as well as some
new updated capabilities you have for
the embed experience inside business
Central and also some new improvements
in our business Central connector for
parbi let me start talking about some
new content we have available for you so
since the first minor update you will
actually have access to some new apps in
preview which contain a lot more than 60
actually different report pages that
cover some of the most used areas inside
business Central these are outof thee
boox reports that you can just use uh
directly from day one since we release
these reports also will make use of some
new functionality we have in the inad
experience and I would like to switch to
a demo and show you this in
action so uh I now switch to my business
Central and you can see that I'm in the
RO Center and I have added with a custom
extension some new links to my R Center
here you can see they're called Finance
or overview so now when I click one of
those links you can see that a powerbi
report opens embedded inside business
Central and it takes all the real estate
that is available on the screen so you
can actually see the report in its full
size this is uh one of the pages of one
of the reports upcoming for the next uh
minor release and you can see that now
the report takes all the space and it
also changes size nicely if the page is
smaller or if the page is larger
and this is of course one way you can ED
the report but as a developer since this
release you have some additional
capabilities here so you can see that uh
you can choose as a developer to embed
the report with much more Rich uh
context from the parbi embed experience
so you can see in this case we have the
filter panes and we have the bookmarks
and different pages in the report I can
switch to and of course this comes with
all the nice filtering and clicking and
drilling capabilities that powerbi
offers out of the box I also would like
to point out that before this release it
was very cumbersome to bookmark one of
these report pages in your business
Central but here you can see that I have
bookmarked this page so when I go back
to the RO Center you will see in my home
bar there is actually the page parbi
Finance which is bookmarked for me so
next time I can find it more easily also
I would like to point out that from this
release these pages are also searchable
so if you search for finance overview
you'll see that my Pages pop up in the
search as well last thing I want to
mention is that uh we also have a better
multilanguage experience for our reports
so for example if I had a user that
speaks French and prefers to see the
reports in French I could just as a
developer specify that in the way I
embed the report and as you can see my
report opened in French now not all of
the labels are translated we are still
working on this so that's why it's
upcoming for a minor release but you can
see that my title for example shows up
in French and so do my uh top insights
in this
report let me now switch from business
Central to visual studio code so I can
show you how the AL code for the
extension I just showed you looks like
you can see here that I just have around
50 lines of code so this is all you need
really to create a page like the one I
showed you just a second ago and you can
see it just requires you to know the
powerbi report you're embedding and then
set in some different options to
customize the user experience to your
own
needs and I would like to just mention
that this was just a sneak peek of the
report but if you want to know more
about the upcoming reports you should
make sure that you also watch the video
that my colleagues are um doing for this
release and that's going to introduce
you more to what is coming what reports
you will have access to and um what's
the story behind all of these new
reports now let me also summarize what
you just saw in a couple of
slides so you saw some new capability is
when embedding reports in business
Central and you as a developer will have
a much more
flexible um framework where you can
choose the experience you want for your
users if you want it to be more flexible
more complete or more simple and
straightforward I also want to mention
that the powerbi addin is now in the
system application which means you can
just make use of it uh directly from
your
app if you're a larger isv and you have
a lot of reports that you want to embed
with in business Central you can use our
code generator this is available in our
bcch repo or directly at the link that
you can see on screen you can use this
and just input an Excel file to the
generator and you'll get out all the AL
pages that you need uh each of them
pointing to the report that you prefer
and you can just uh that way have a much
easier maintenance of your extension
that uh uses powerbi
integration you also saw some sneak peek
on our multilanguage support from this
release multilanguage support is baked
into a platform level so it's actually
directly inside the powerbi report which
means you don't need to have uh web
services for example that expose
different languages labels you can just
have everything inside the powerbi
report so as a report Creator and
especially as an isv you have a much
easier time building your reports and
distributing them to your customers we
have also in bch a tool that you can use
to embed the translations inside your
PBX file so make sure you go there and
have a look at the rhy files to
understand how this works in
practice another set of improvements we
introduced is regarding the powerbi
connector for business Central we have
added some new options so that you as a
report Creator can have more flexibility
when it comes to uh the way the report
should refresh and connect to business
Central notice that these already
default to what we think is the best
value for them um so you don't really
need to customize those but you might
have some specific scenario that
requires you to specify for example a
different timeout for the O data queries
and from this release you can do that
and you can take full advantage of our
connector thank you for your attention
this is all we have for you today thanks
a lot